A Guide to the Papers of Charles J. Faulkner, 1846-1890
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Charles J. Faulkner 1846-1890
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
38-230
13 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These papers were a gift of Atcheson Laughlin Hench, ca. 1936.
Scope and Content
13 items, 1846-1890, of Charles James Faulkner (1806-1884), primarily concerning his litigation with John E. Boyd on real estate, together with some papers of his son, Charles James Faulkner (1847-1929), chiefly re: requests for senatorial patronage. The collection contains letters of Governor Emanuel Willis Wilson (1844-1905) and Senator Johnson Newlon Camden (1828-1908), a real estate developer, politician, and senator from West Virginia (1893-1895).
Contents List
- Note of settlement of debts between Faulkner and John E. Boyd 1872 June 24, AMS
- Transcript of judgment and lien against real estate of John E. Boyd in Berkeley County, West Virginia 1874 May, AM
- Receipt, Casper Stump to Faulkner for amount awarded in Faulkner vs. Boyd 1876 July 2, AMS
- E.W. Wilson, Charleston, West Virginia to Faulkner, Martinsburg, West Virginia, re: interruption of Gov. Wilson's review by a meeting of the Board of Public Works 1876 July 2, ALS
- Anna A. Gallaher, [Washington, D.C.], to Senator Camden, asking for assistance with her debts 1887 July 17, ALS
- J.N. C[amden], New York, to "My dear Judge," enclosing letter from Gallaher 1887 July 20, ALS
- J.B. Sommerville, Wheeling, West Virginia, to Faulkner, Martinsburg, Virginia, requests patronage on behalf of Ira Mitchell of Wellsburg 1887 Oct. 24, TL
- John J. Jacob, Wheeling, West Virginia, to Faulkner, asking him to attend a convention of representatives from various bar associations 1888 May 5, LS
- Conrad H[unt] Syme, Washington, D.C., to Faulkner, re: political news of West Virginia 1890 Nov. 9, LS
- J.N. Camden, Parkersburg [West Virginia], to "My dear Faulkner"; expresses pleasures that Faulkner will get a place for Shaffeer; Oldham is the right man for PM at Moundsville n.y. June 29, ALS
- J[ohn] E. Boyd to Faulkner, concerning Mr. Hode, the writer's financial troubles, a plan to sell property, and a mill n.d., ALS
- Legal citations n.d., TM